John A. Holmes Papers MS007
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Poetry, 1922 -- 1962; 1940 -- 1961; MS007.001; 7.25 Linear Feet; 1 Audiovisual Object(s)
  - The wind in the elm trees, 1953; MS007.001.006.00712; Holmes, John (Box 6)
    Box 6 folder 109. Annotated. Revision in 6:110 is annotated. Revision in 6:111 is titled "Unfinished Poem (for Doris)". Revisions in 10:035, p. 74-80 are all untitled and annotated. Published in University of Kansas City Review, 20:58-9, Autumn 1953. revisions in 6:110; 6:111; 10:035, p. 74; 10:035, p. 75; 10:035, p. 76; 10:035, p. 77; 10:035, p. 78; 10:035, p. 79; 10:035, p. 80; 10:035, p. 81-85; 10:035, p. 88-91; 10:035, p. 82-84; 10:37; p. 4
  - A wish, 1950-05-01; MS007.001.006.00713; Holmes, John (Box 6)
    Box 6 folder 112. Published in The double root, p. 27; Hopkins Review, 4:25, Fall 1950; New York Times, January 8 1956; New York Times Book Review, July 22 1962, p. 2.
  - The word heart, 1939; MS007.001.006.00714; Holmes, John (Box 6)
    Box 6 folder 113. Duplicate in 10:010, p. 124 & 10:035, p. 157 is titled: "Notes on a word" Published as "Word Heart" in Ladies Home Journal, 56:73, January 1939. duplicates in 10:010, p. 124 and 10:035, p. 157
  - World the way it is, 1947; MS007.001.006.00715; Holmes, John (Box 6)
    Box 6 folder 114. Published in The double root, p. 15; Atlantic, 180:69, July 1947. revisions in 6:115 and 10:033, p. 10A
  - Dream, 1926-12-01; MS007.001.007.00716; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 001.
  - Figure of speech, MS007.001.007.00717; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 002.
  - For D.H., 1925; MS007.001.007.00718; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 003. Handwritten Autumn 1925
  - I can never be alone, MS007.001.007.00719; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 004. Annotated
  - In cities, MS007.001.007.00720; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 005.
  - Interior, MS007.001.007.00721; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 006. Revision in 10:034, p. 99 is handwritten. revisions in 10:034, p. 99
  - Young man's poem, 1935; MS007.001.007.00722; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 007. Published in Address to the living, p. 18; Commonweal, 21:733, April 26, 1935; Fiction Parade and Golden Book Magazine, 2:321, January 1936. revision in 10:010, p. 61 and duplicate in 10:034, p. 70
  - Tireless testament [Testament], 1935; MS007.001.007.00723; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 007. Revisions in 10:010 & 10:014 are titled: Testament. Published as "Testament" in Address to the living, p. 23.; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1935, (New York: Poetry Digest Association, 1936) p. 74; Present Tense, Rev. ed. (New York: Harcourt, Brace, 1945) p. 736; Atlantic, 155:56, January 1935; Modern Literature, 3:6, May 15-31, 1935; Hartford Daily Times, January 25 1935; New York Herald-Tribune, January 20 1935. revisions in 8:019; 10:014; 10:010, p. 66
  - The chest of time, MS007.001.007.00724; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 007. revisions in 8:041; 10:010, p. 68; 10:034, p. 73; 10:035, p. 143
  - Brother to brother, 1859, 1934; MS007.001.007.00725; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 007. Revision in 10:038, p. 14 is titled: "Brother to brother: a letter" Published in Address to the living, p. 65; Yankee Poetry Chapbook, p. 12-13, Autumn 1934. duplicate in 10:010, p. 64, revisions in 10:034, p. 71 and 10:038, p. 14
  - The phoenix promise, MS007.001.007.00726; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 007. Revision in 10:010 is annotated. Published in Address to the living, p. 48.
  - At a country fair, 1937; MS007.001.007.00727; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 008. Published in Fair warning, p. 43; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1937, (New York: Paebar, 1938), p. 79; The Moon is Shining Bright as Day (Philadelphia: Lippincott, 1953) p. 157; New Yorker, 13:21, September 18, 1937; Waterbury, Connecticut American, October 13, 1937. revision in 10:010, p. 128
  - Fable, MS007.001.007.00728; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 008.
  - In danger safely, MS007.001.007.00729; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 008. Published in Map of my country, p. 45 revision in 11:002, p. 47
  - Aware of legends, MS007.001.007.00730; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 010.
  - Diver, MS007.001.007.00731; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 012.
  - Death in the back yard, 1958; MS007.001.007.00732; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 013. Revision in 10:037, p. 112 is annotated. Published in The fortune teller, p. 68; Anthology of Magazine Verse for 1958 (New York: Schulte, 1959) p. 104; Best Poems of 1958 (Palo Alto, CA: Pacific Books, 1960) p. 44; Best Articles and Stories, 2:36-27, November 1958; Saturday Review, 41:27, July 26, 1958. revisions in 10:037, p. 112 and 11:003, p. 57, sound recording in 67:001
  - The expectation [Expectations], 1959; MS007.001.007.00733; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 013. Duplicate in 10:037, p. 139 and revision in 11:003, p. 63 are titled: "Expectations" Published as "Expectations" in The fortune teller, p. 81; Harper, 219:79, September 1959. duplicate in 10:037, p. 139 and revision in 11:003, p. 63
  - O Lord of stars and sunlight, MS007.001.007.00734; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 013. Revision in 9:017 is titled: Words for a hymn. Set to music as hymn of same title in Hymns for the Celebration of Life, Boston: Beacon Press, 1964. Published in Chautauqua Bell Tower, 13:1, April 1949. revisions in 9:017 and 10:037, p. 65
  - Lady is a lady, 1958; MS007.001.007.00735; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 013. Revision in 10:037, p. 118 is annotated. Revision in 10:037, p. 118 was originally titled: "On a lady's saying she hears great things of me but not saying more" Published in The fortune teller, p. 17; Saturday Review, 41:38, November 22, 1958. revision in 10:037, p. 118; duplicate in 11:003, p. 15; sound recording in 66:001
  - The long walk alone [Renewal], 1934; MS007.001.007.00736; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 014. Revision in 9:107 dated: July 1933. Published in Address to the living, p. 76; Virginia Quarterly Review, 10:54, January 1934. revisions in 9:107; 10:038, p. 19; 7:024; duplicate in 10:034, p. 63
  - Odd moment, 1936; MS007.001.007.00737; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 014. Revision in 10:010 is annotated. Published in Address to the living, p. 75; Fiction Parade and Golden Book Magazine, 4:347, January 1937; Scribner's, 49:89, February 1936. revision in 10:010, p. 80
  - The good, the great, the wise, 1935; MS007.001.007.00738; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 014. Published in Address to the living, p. 101; Atlantic, 156:172, August 1935. duplicates in 10:010, p. 99 and 10:038, p. 26
  - The secret tide, 1936; MS007.001.007.00739; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 014. Published in Address to the living, p. 102; Atlantic, 158:349, September 1936. revision in 10:010, p. 100
  - The mountain farm, MS007.001.007.00740; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 017. revision in 9:090
  - An old song with a new refrain, MS007.001.007.00741; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 018. revision in 7:019
  - Penny for your thoughts, MS007.001.007.00742; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 021. Handwritten. Revision in 7:022 is titled: "A penny for your thoughts". Revision in 10:034, p. 96 is handwritten. revisions in 7:022 and 10:034, p. 96
  - Portrait two, MS007.001.007.00743; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 023.
  - Street scene, MS007.001.007.00744; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 025.
  - The summer after, MS007.001.007.00745; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 026. Part of Collection called "Six poems from the coast of Maine"; Revision in 8:008 revision in 8:008, duplicate in 10:034, p. 81
  - Remembered nights, MS007.001.007.00746; Holmes, John (Box 7)
  - Moonrise, MS007.001.007.00747; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 026. Part of Collection called "Six poems from the coast of Maine" duplicates in 8:008 and 10:034, p. 82
  - Nine o'clock, MS007.001.007.00748; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 026. Part of Collection called "Six poems from the coast of Maine"; Revision in 8:008 revision in 8:008; duplicate in 10:034, p. 82
  - Once in August, MS007.001.007.00749; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 026. Part of Collection called "Six poems from the coast of Maine"; revision in 8:008 revision in 8:008
  - The time is good, MS007.001.007.00750; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 027.
  - The winter, 1926-12-01; MS007.001.007.00751; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 029.
  - The apple, MS007.001.007.00752; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 033. Revision in 10:035, p. 167 is titled: "Man to man" revision in 10:035, p. 167
  - Voices in a new world, MS007.001.007.00753; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 033.
  - The woman who would not close her eyes, MS007.001.007.00754; Holmes, John (Box 7)
  - Green things growing, 1928; MS007.001.007.00755; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 034. duplicate in 10:034, p. 17, revision in 10:034, p. 122
  - Death of a leaf, 1961-06-01; MS007.001.007.00756; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 035. Revision in 7:038 is titled: The leaf. Revision in 7:039 & 7:040 is titled: House-leaf. Revision in 7:040 is dated June 1961. revisions in 7:036, 7:037; 7:038; 7:039; June 1961, 7:040; 10:037, p. 169
  - Come and play, MS007.001.007.00757; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 043. revision in 10:034, p. 84
  - Moment, MS007.001.007.00758; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 043. revision in 8:024, duplicate in 10:034, p. 84
  - Fears, MS007.001.007.00759; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 044.
  - He knows it is safe, MS007.001.007.00760; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 046.
  - Is calm the thing?, 1927-06-01; MS007.001.007.00761; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 049.
  - Maybe tomorrow, 1933-02-01; MS007.001.007.00762; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 051. Duplicate in 7:051 dated February 1933. duplicate, February 1933, 7:051
  - Not you like music, MS007.001.007.00763; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 052. Revision in 9:074 is annotated. revisions in 9:074 and 10:034, p. 106
  - O Time!, MS007.001.007.00764; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 053.
  - On finding certain lines marked in Santayana's sonnets, MS007.001.007.00765; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 054. Annotated. Revision in 7:055 is titled: On finding certain marked lines in the Santayana sonnets. Revision in 10:035, p. 133 is titled: On finding marked lines. revisions in 7:055; 9:070; 10:010, p. 31; 10:034, p. 48; 10:035, p. 133
  - Plainly said, 1928-12-16; MS007.001.007.00766; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 057. Annotated: " From a group called 'One of Three'"
  - Prayer for to-morrow, 1926-12-01; MS007.001.007.00767; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 058.
  - Sonnet to a friend twice my age, MS007.001.007.00768; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 070.
  - Things I love, 1930-05-19; MS007.001.007.00769; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 071. revisions in 7:072 and 8:015
  - Wars that rage: sonnet, 1926; MS007.001.007.00770; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 074.
  - The watcher in the street, MS007.001.007.00771; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 075. Annotated revision in 8:120
  - Weave a circle round him, 1928-12-16; MS007.001.007.00772; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 076. Annotated: "from a group called 'One of Three'" revision in 7:117
  - Young promise, MS007.001.007.00773; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 077. revisions in 9:019; 10:010, p. 31; 10:034, p. 41; 10:035, p. 132
  - Page in a diary: For Doris to remember the day by, 1953-08-01; MS007.001.007.00774; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 078. Two copies, one annotated. duplicate in 10:035, p. 8
  - Pain I gave you, MS007.001.007.00775; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 079.
  - A penny poem, MS007.001.007.00776; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 081. Revision in 10:037, p. 174 is annotated. revision in 10:037, p. 173
  - Perfectly deathless poem to Betty Rosenthal from John Holmes on receiving a necktie, MS007.001.007.00777; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 083.
  - Photographer's Sunday, MS007.001.007.00778; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 084. Revision in 10:037, p. 152 is annotated. revisions in 7:085; 7:086; 7:087; 10:037, p. 152
  - Plato's table, MS007.001.007.00779; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 088. Annotated; revision in 7:089 (annotated); revision in 7:090 (annotated); revision in 7:091 (annotated-only P. 1); revision in 7:092 (annotated); revision in 7:093 (annotated on back); revision in 7:094 (annotated-only P. 1); revision in 7:095 (annotated-only P. 1); revision in 7:096 (annotated); revision in 7:097 (annotated); revision in 7:098 entitled "Plato's Table". revisions in 7:089; 7:090; 7:091; 7:092; 7:093; 7:094; 7:095; 7:096; 7:097; 7:098; 10:037, p. 170
  - Poem for my 32nd birthday, MS007.001.007.00780; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 100. Annotated
  - Poetry [Living for poetry], 1933-01-01; MS007.001.007.00781; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 102. Annotated Published in Voices, 80:4-5, February-March 1935. Date could be 1933-02. revisions in 10:010, p. 44; 10:034, p. 51; 10:011; 10:038, p. 22.
  - Whatever winds, MS007.001.007.00782; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 104.
  - Reflection of a shadow, 1928-09-01; MS007.001.007.00783; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 106.
  - The responsibilities, 1950-03-01; MS007.001.007.00784; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 107. revision in 7:108
  - Rhyme of going to the store [Going to the store], 1929; MS007.001.007.00785; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 109. Published as "Going to the store" in Fair warning, p. 60; Boston Herald, April 16 1929.
  - Shake well, throw away, 1946-09-01; MS007.001.007.00786; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 112.
  - Should I?, MS007.001.007.00787; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 113. Annotated
  - Sky once more, MS007.001.007.00788; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 114. revisions in7:115 and 9:110
  - Some in dreams, MS007.001.007.00789; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 117.
  - Song, MS007.001.007.00790; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 118.
  - Sonnet to a dancing-partner, MS007.001.007.00791; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 120.
  - Sort of spring song, with ah!, 1954-04-12; MS007.001.007.00792; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 121. revision in 10:036, p. 25
  - So you will know, MS007.001.007.00793; Holmes, John (Box 7)
    Box 7 folder 125. revision in 10:010, p. 117
  - Spring: a sermon [The double root], 1947-04-01; MS007.001.008.00794; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 003. Annotated. Revisions in 9:100-3 are annotated. Published in The double root, p. 53; Epoch, 2:109, Winter 1949. Printed on Christmas card for 1948. Includes version of the poem entitled "The Double Root", in a clipping from What Unitarians Believe, summer 1987. revision in 9:100; 9:101; 9:102; 9:103; 9:104; 9:105; 10:033, p. 45; 10:018
  - Spring morning, MS007.001.008.00795; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 004.
  - Subject for a poem, MS007.001.008.00796; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 005.
  - Suddenly birds, MS007.001.008.00797; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 006. revision in 8:007
  - Sword on the wall, MS007.001.008.00798; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 010. duplicate in 10:010, p. 62; revisions in 10:034, p. 134 and 10:035, p. 140
  - Take a lot of people, MS007.001.008.00799; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 011. Revision in 10:036, p. 66 is annotated: "attempt at a ballad, on reading that someone had once written "NOTS TO PEOPLE" in N.Y. subway. Revision 10:036, p. 66 is crossed out. revisions in 8:012; 10:036, p. 66; 10:036, p. 89
  - The tall men, 1950; MS007.001.008.00800; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 013. Printed on Christmas card for 1950. duplicates in 10:035, p. 104 and 10:037, p. 16
  - The Passing king, MS007.001.008.00801; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 014. Handwritten
  - To one I dislike, MS007.001.008.00802; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 014.
  - A thing to say, 1960; MS007.001.008.00803; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 017. Published in Reflections (s l: n p, 1960) p. 25. Date is estimated revision in 10:037, p. 131
  - Time's noise, MS007.001.008.00804; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 018. Two copies, one annotated.
  - ...To a desert island, MS007.001.008.00805; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 020. revisions in 8:021 and 10:037, p. 116
  - Advice, MS007.001.008.00806; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 022. Revision in 10:010, p. 112 & 10:035, p. 156 is titled: "Advice in vain". Revision in 10:010, p. 112 is annotated. revisions in 8:023; 10:010, p. 112; 10:035, p. 156
  - Against growing old, MS007.001.008.00807; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 024.
  - Average reader, MS007.001.008.00808; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 028. revisions in 10:010, p. 147 and 10:035, p. 162
  - Belladonna, MS007.001.008.00809; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 030.
  - Big girl now, MS007.001.008.00810; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 031. duplicate in 10:037, p. 121
  - Book-review, MS007.001.008.00811; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 032.
  - Bumps in the night, 1962; MS007.001.008.00812; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 034. Revision in 8:039 dated: March 1962 revisions in 8:035; 8:036; 8:037; 8:038; 10:037, p. 172
  - Children try, MS007.001.008.00813; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 042. revision in 8:043
  - Clouds on a summer night, MS007.001.008.00814; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 046.
  - Country quiet remembered, MS007.001.008.00815; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 049. revision in 10:033, p. 37
  - Curse, MS007.001.008.00816; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 050.
  - Deep shore, MS007.001.008.00817; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 052. Revision in 10:035, p. 159 is titled: Deep tide revisions in 10:010, p. 136 and 10:035, p. 159
  - Dorothy, 1962-04-23; MS007.001.008.00818; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 053. revision in 8:054
  - The druids, 1946-02-01; MS007.001.008.00819; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 055.
  - At night, 1924-07-01; MS007.001.008.00820; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 056.
  - Epitaph for Peter if he should die, MS007.001.008.00821; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 057.
  - Essay of saints, MS007.001.008.00822; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 058. revision in 8:059
  - Examination, 1945-10-09; MS007.001.008.00823; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 061.
  - An exercise in humility, 1949-10-22; MS007.001.008.00824; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 062.
  - Ezra Pound, MS007.001.008.00825; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 063.
  - The face, 1933-02-01; MS007.001.008.00826; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 064. Annotated
  - Wings, MS007.001.008.00827; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 069. Handwritten
  - Four friends, MS007.001.008.00828; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 071.
  - Gathering poem [Your move], 1949-04-15; MS007.001.008.00829; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 073. Annotated. Revisions in 9:021, 9:022, 9:023, 9:084, 9:085 are titled: Your move. Revision in 9:023 is annotated. revisions in March 9, 1962, 9:021; 9:022; March 6, 1962, 9:023; 9:084; 9:085
  - Golden egg, 1954-03-14; MS007.001.008.00830; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 074.
  - Hullaballou, MS007.001.008.00831; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 077. Collection of "Four songs for 'Hullaballou'" revision in 10:037, p. 103
  - Holy Ballou, MS007.001.008.00832; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 078. Collection of "Four songs for 'Hullaballou'" duplicate in 10:037, p. 102
  - Hello Ballou, MS007.001.008.00833; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 079. Collection of "Four songs for 'Hullaballou'" duplicate in 10:037, p. 102
  - Hail Ballou, MS007.001.008.00834; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 080. Collection of "Four songs for 'Hullaballou'" revision in 10:037, p. 101
  - The hamlet, 1949-04-01; MS007.001.008.00835; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 081. Revision in 8:082 is annotated. Revision in 8:093 is titled: To a waverer. Revision in 8:093 is annotated. duplicate in 8:081, revisions in 8:082; 8:093; 8:094; 8:095
  - Hearing them speak, MS007.001.008.00836; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 083. Annotated. Revision in 10:034, p. 119 is annotated. revisions in 8:084 and 10:034, p. 119
  - His dazzled look [The look], 1957-12-01; MS007.001.008.00837; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 086. Slightly different version entitled "The Look", added June 2009. revisions in December 1957, 9:042 and 10:037, p. 116
  - How do I love thee?, MS007.001.008.00838; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 088. revisions in 8:089 and 10:037, p. 162
  - To a friend too kind, MS007.001.008.00839; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 091. Annotated.
  - To be tacked on the bulletin board at any writers' conference, MS007.001.008.00840; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 096.
  - To Isabel with some poems, 1933-09-21; MS007.001.008.00841; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 097.
  - Twenty eight Billingham Street, 1956-03-09; MS007.001.008.00842; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 100. Annotated: "(written as an exercise, which I had given my poetry class: the rhyme-scheme was fixed, and all of us used the same one. The agreed subject was to be a memory brought back by an odor. I'm describing the first house, and the first coal-furnace that was my responsibility, when I was first married.)"
  - Two men talking, 1940-02-14; MS007.001.008.00843; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 101. Annotated.
  - Understandable poem [To a Neighbor], 1956; MS007.001.008.00844; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 102. Two copies of a slightly different version, entitled "To a Neighbor" and dedicated to Mary Bacon, added June 2009
  - The visiting poets, MS007.001.008.00845; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 104. Revisions in 8:016, 8:108, 8:109, 8:110, 8:111, 8:112, 8:113, 8:114, 8:116, 8:117 are annotated. Revision in 8:112 is titled: The five. Revision in 8:117 is annotated also on back. Revision in 10:037, p. 181 is annotated. revisions in 8:106; 8:107; 8:108; 8:109; 8:110; 8:111; 8:112; 8:113; 8:114; 8:116; 8:117; 10:037, p. 155; 10:037, p. 181
  - Cal Lowell [The visiting poets], MS007.001.008.00846; Holmes, John (Box 8)
    Box 8 folder 105.
  - We are waiting, 1953-11-01; MS007.001.009.00847; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 001. revisions in 9:002 and 10:035, p. 17
  - Wherever you lie, MS007.001.009.00848; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 005. Revision in 9:006 is annotated. Revision in 10:010 is crossed out. revisions in 9:006; 9:007; 10:010, p. 138
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.009.00849; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 007.
  - Window, 1946-08-01; MS007.001.009.00850; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 010. Revision in 9:011 dated August 1946. revisions in August 1946, 9:011; 9:012; 9:013; 10:033, p. 40
  - Word from the west, 1945-10-09; MS007.001.009.00851; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 014.
  - Words are so exciting, MS007.001.009.00852; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 016.
  - The young men speaking, MS007.001.009.00853; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 018.
  - [Untitled], MS007.001.009.00854; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 024.
  - Hush, MS007.001.009.00855; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 025.
  - I do it myself [I always did], 1955-10-14; MS007.001.009.00856; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 027. Annotated. Revision in 9:113 is handwritten. revisions in 9:113 and 10:037, p. 70
  - In a dark wood, MS007.001.009.00857; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 028. revision in 10:037, p. 4
  - A kind of silence, MS007.001.009.00858; Holmes, John (Box 9)
    Box 9 folder 031. Revision in 10:001 titled "The Island" revision in 10:001